<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Cognitive Measures</string>

    <string name="agreement">The following are a series of cognitive tasks, several of which are the versions of the tasks you completed in the original Project Talent
        study.\n\n
        \t&#8226; Read the instructions for each task carefully.\n
        \t&#8226; Do the best you can. If you are unsure of the right answer, pick the one you think is the best.\n
        \t&#8226; If a task includes multiple-choice questions, select only one answer.\n
        \t&#8226; There is only one right answer for each question.\n\n
        Press the NEXT button to begin the first task.</string>
    <string name="finish_message">Please click "Finish" to proceed into next section.</string>

    <string name="begin">Begin</string>
    <string name="button_str_back">Back</string>
    <string name="finishbutton_str">Finish</string>

    <!-- Vocabulary strings -->
    <string name="vo_text">INSTRUCTIONS\n\n
		This task contains words for you to define. The items are multiple choice - select the best response for each word.
    </string>
    <string name="vocabulary">Vocabulary</string>
    <string name="vocab3">
          [
            {
               \"question\": \"A vacuum is a space containing\",
               \"options\": [\"Ozone\",
                        \"Helium\",
                        \"Carbon monoxide\",
                        \"Nitrogen\",
                        \"Nothing\"
                        ],
                \"answer\": 4
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"To surrender means to\",
                \"options\": [\"Fight\",
                       \"Conquer\",
                        \"Retreat\",
                        \"Surround\",
                        \"Yield\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 4
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"Obstruction means\",
                \"options\": [\"Obeisance\",
                        \"Obstacle\",
                        \"Obstinacy\",
                        \"Obstreperousness\",
                        \"Obtuseness\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 1
            }
          ]
    </string>
    <string name="vocab1">
         [
            {
               \"question\": \"A diagram is a kind of\",
               \"options\": [\"Route\",
                        \"Building\",
                        \"Measurement\",
                        \"Drawing\",
                        \"Grammatical error\"
                        ],
                \"answer\": 3
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"To discard is to\",
                \"options\": [\"Gamble\",
                       \"Hide\",
                        \"Lie\",
                        \"Take away\",
                        \"Throw away\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 4
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"Blunt means\",
                \"options\": [\"Heavy\",
                        \"Dangerous\",
                        \"Weak\",
                        \"Sharp\",
                        \"Dull\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 4
            }
          ]
    </string>
    <string name="vocab2">
         [
            {
               \"question\": \"Which of these is not a measuring device?\",
               \"options\": [\"Caliper\",
                        \"Protractor\",
                        \"Voltmeter\",
                        \"Gauge\",
                        \"Solder\"
                        ],
                \"answer\": 4
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"A purpose of lubrication is to\",
                \"options\": [\"Prevent motion\",
                       \"Increase heat\",
                        \"Reduce friction\",
                        \"Prevent warping\",
                        \"Remove dirt\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 2
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"Restricted means\",
                \"options\": [\"Scolded\",
                        \"Redesigned\",
                        \"Limited\",
                        \"Refrained\",
                        \"Tense\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 2
            }
          ]
    </string>
    <string name="vocab4">
         [
            {
               \"question\": \"To retain means to\",
               \"options\": [\"Get\",
                        \"Give up\",
                        \"Keep\",
                        \"Lose\",
                        \"Create\"
                        ],
                \"answer\": 2
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"A municipal court is a\",
                \"options\": [\"City court\",
                       \"State court\",
                        \"Federal court\",
                        \"United Nations court\",
                        \"Military court\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 0
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"Which of these is carnivorous?\",
                \"options\": [\"Chipmunk\",
                        \"Cow\",
                        \"Horse\",
                        \"Tiger\",
                        \"Elephant\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 3
            }
          ]
    </string>
    <string name="vocab5">
         [
            {
               \"question\": \"Magnitude means\",
               \"options\": [\"Generosity\",
                        \"Size\",
                        \"Location\",
                        \"Kindness\",
                        \"Direction\"
                        ],
                \"answer\": 1
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"Eccentric means\",
                \"options\": [\"Odd\",
                       \"Feeble-minded\",
                        \"Stingy\",
                        \"Temperamental\",
                        \"Solitary\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 0
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"A barometer is used to measure\",
                \"options\": [\"Temperature\",
                        \"Rainfall\",
                        \"Humidity\",
                        \"Air pressure\",
                        \"Cloudiness\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 3
            }
          ]
    </string>
    <!-- Vocabulary strings -->

    <!-- Number Series -->
    <string name="ns_section_title">Number Series</string>
    <string name="ns_instr"> Please enter the number that belongs in each empty box. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_sec_nsex2_a_">Example 2 Answer</string>
    <string name="ns_intro">You will now see six more questions like the ones you just did.\n\n
		Instructions:\n
		&#8226; Please enter the number that belongs in each empty box.\n
		&#8226; An empty box could be at the end of a series or it could be in the middle.\n
		&#8226; You may be asked a question with more than one empty box in the sequence.\n
		&#8226; The numbers might increase, like 2, 4, 6, or decrease, like 6, 4, 2.\n
		&#8226; Some of the items may be easy but others may be hard. Just do the best you can.\n
		&#8226; It is more important to answer the item correctly than to answer quickly, so take a little time to think before answering.\n
		&#8226; In a few cases, more than one number may be correct. Please give only one answer per box. If your answer is one of the correct answers, you will receive credit.\n
		&#8226; You can go on to the next item at any time by clicking \'Next\'.\n\n
		If you are ready to begin, please click \'Next\'.
	</string>
    <string name="nsq">Please enter the number that belongs in each empty box.</string>
    <string name="clear">Undo</string>
    <string name="clicknext">Please click \'Next\' to continue.</string>
    <string name="ns_example1">
        {
          \"id\": 1,
          \"question\": \"Instructions: In this task, on each screen you will be presented with several numbers that make up a series. There will be one or more empty boxes
        somewhere in the series. Sometimes the empty boxes will be at the end of the series, and sometimes they will be in the middle. Press the number buttons to enter the
        number that goes in each empty box.\n\n
		For example:\",
         \"options\": [1, 2, 3, 4],
         \"ansPosition\": 2,
          \"answerText\": \"The answer we were looking for is 3, so the completed sequence is:\"
        }
    </string>
    <string name="ns_example2">
        {
          \"id\": 2,
          \"question\": \"Below is another example.\",
          \"options\": [2, 4, 6, 8],
          \"ansPosition\": 3,
          \"answerText\": \"The answer we were looking for is 8 because the numbers (2, 4, 6, 8) increase by 2. The completed sequence is:\"
        }
    </string>
    <string name="ns_3">
        [
          {
            \"options\": [8, 10, 12, 14],
            \"ansPosition\": 1
          },
          {
            \"options\": [23, 26, 30, 35, 41],
            \"ansPosition\": 4
          },
          {
            \"options\": [18, 17, 15, 12, 8],
            \"ansPosition\": 3
          }
        ]
    </string>
    <string name="ns_1">
        [
          {
            \"options\": [6, 7, 8, 9],
            \"ansPosition\": 2
          },
          {
            \"options\": [6, 5, 4, 3],
            \"ansPosition\": 1
          },
          {
            \"options\": [5, 8, 11, 14],
            \"ansPosition\": 3
          }
        ]
    </string>
    <string name="ns_2">
        [
          {
            \"options\": [2, 4, 6, 8],
            \"ansPosition\": 0
          },
          {
            \"options\": [1, 3, 3, 5, 7, 7, 9],
            \"ansPosition\": 6
          },
          {
            \"options\": [18, 10, 6, 4, 3],
            \"ansPosition\": 3
          }
        ]
    </string>
    <string name="ns_4">
        [
          {
            \"options\": [17, 15, 12, 8],
            \"ansPosition\": 1
          },
          {
            \"options\": [10, 6, 3, 1],
            \"ansPosition\": 1
          },
          {
            \"options\": [17, 16, 14, 10, 2],
            \"ansPosition\": 4,
            \"ansOptions\": [2, 3]
          }
        ]
    </string>
    <string name="ns_5">
        [
          {
            \"options\": [17, 20, 26, 38, 62],
            \"ansPosition\": 0
          },
          {
            \"options\": [5, 7, 11, 19, 35],
            \"ansPosition\": 1
          },
          {
            \"options\": [70, 72, 76, 84],
            \"ansPosition\": 1,
            \"ansPositions\": [1, 2],
            \"ansMultiOptions\": [[72, 76], [78, 82]]
          }
        ]
    </string>
    <!-- Number series -->

    <!-- Abstract reasoning -->
    <string name="ar_section_title">Abstract Reasoning</string>
    <string name="ar_text">Instructions\n\n
		Each item in this task consists of a set of figures arranged in a pattern, formed according to certain rules. Look at the following patterns in example.
	</string>
    <string name="ar_text1">The question mark in the lower right corner of the box shows where a figure is missing in the pattern. You are to decide which of the five
        figures under the pattern belongs where the question mark is.\n\n
        Please click \"Next\" to continue.</string>

    <string name="ar_text3">In the case of the example above, the figure in the bottom left is larger than the one above it but otherwise
        same. In the top row, the figure at the right is the same as the one to the left of it except that it has been turned upside down. Following these rules,
        the missing figure should be larger than the one above it, and exactly the same size as the one to the left of it, but upside down. Therefore, the choice
        selected is the correct answer.\n\n
        Please click \"Next\" to continue.
	</string>

    <string name="practice">PRACTICE EXAMPLE</string>
    <string name="practiceq1">Here is a practice item.  Select the figure that completes the pattern then press \"Next\". </string>
    <string name="ar_instr1">In each problem, you are to decide what figure belongs where the question mark is in the pattern. To do this you have to figure out what
        the rule is according to which the drawings change, going from row to row, and what the rule is for the changes going from column to column. The items have
        different kinds of patterns and different rules by which the drawings change.\n\nPlease click Next to continue.</string>

    <string name="practiceq2">Now look at another problem, which is quite different from either of the previous ones.\n\n
    Choose the answer that belongs in \"?\" below, then click Next to continue.</string>
    <string name="pr_wrong">Going from left to right, the circles get larger, and going from top to bottom they get darker.
        Therefore
        the answer has to be a circle which is the largest of the three sizes, and the darkest. Choices 3 and 5 are both the right size, but 5 is the only large circle
        with the correct shading. Thus 5 is the only drawing that fits in the pattern formed by the other circles. 5 is the answer that should be chosen.\n\n
        Please click \"Next\" to continue.
	</string>
    <string name="pr_explain">What is the missing figure here? If you study the pattern you will see that going from left to right there is one more line in each figure
        than in the one to the left of it. Going from top to bottom, the number of lines in any figure is one less than in the figure just above it. Therefore, the
        missing figure should have three lines. The answer is choice 3 (the three lines, slanting in the proper direction).\n\n
        Please click \"Next\" to continue.</string>
    <string name="ar_intro">INSTRUCTIONS\n\n
		&#8226; You will now be asked six more questions like the ones you just did. \n
		&#8226; For each problem, decide what rules the pattern follows. Choose the answer that belongs in \"?\" by clicking the answer below it.\n
		&#8226; Many of the patterns are based on rules that are different from the ones in the sample items.  \n
		&#8226; Do not spend too much time on any one problem. \n\n
		If you are ready to begin, please click \"Next\".
	</string>
    <string name="start_now">Start Now</string>
    <string name="start_task">Would you like to see another example, or are you ready to start this task?</string>
    <string name="example">Another example</string>
    <string name="start_task_confirm">Start task</string>
    <string name="ar_instr">Choose the answer that belongs in \"?\" below, then click \"Next\" to continue.</string>
    <!-- Abstract reasoning -->

    <!-- 2D visualization -->
    <string name="sp_1_instr">Look at the drawings below. The first drawing is shaped like the letter L. The rest of the drawings are like the first, except that they
    have been turned in different directions. </string>
    <string name="sp_next">Please click \"Next\" to continue.</string>
    <string name="sp_1_sol"> If you think of the drawing at the left below as being made out of wire and lying on a table, the positions shown in each of the other four
        drawings could be taken simply by turning the wire figure at the left around, without lifting it off the table. </string>
    <string name="sp_2_instr">Now look at the next row of drawings. The first drawing is shaped like the letter P. But even if the rest of the drawings were turned
        around, they would still be backwards; you would have to lift the figure at the left off the table and flip it over to make any of the other figures. </string>
    <string name="sp_intro"> In this test each problem has one drawing at the left and five similar drawings to the right of it but only one of the five drawings on the
        right exactly matches the drawing at the left if you turn it around. The rest of the drawings are backwards even when they are turned around.</string>
    <string name="sp_3_instr">Now look at the sample problem below.\nWhich one of the choices, when turned around, exactly matches the diagram at the left?</string>
    <string name="sp_3_sol">You should have picked choice D. All of the other choices have been "lifted off the table and flipped over" as well as turned around,
        and thus are backwards. For the sample problem, the answer D has been selected.</string>
    <string name="sp_begin">For each problem in this test, choose the one drawing which, when turned around or rotated, is exactly like the basic drawing at the left.\n\n
        If you are ready to begin, please click \"Next\".</string>
    <string name="sp_question">Choose the one drawing which, when turned around or rotated, is exactly like the basic drawing at the left.</string>
    <!-- 2D visualization -->

    <!-- Warning messages -->
    <string name="quit">Quit</string>
    <string name="resume">Resume</string>
    <string name="timeup">2 minutes up</string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="msg2">You have not submitted a response yet.Your answers are important to us.\nPlease try to answer as best you can. If you are not willing to provide
        an answer, please press NEXT to continue.</string>
    <string name="msg3">You did not complete the question. Your answers are important to us. Please try to answer as best you can. If you are not willing to provide an
        answer, please press NEXT to continue.</string>
    <string name="quit_resume">Would you like to quit? Or go back to where you left off?</string>
    <!-- Warning messages -->

    <!--Context switch -->
    <string name="switch_ns">Switch to number section.</string>
    <string name="switch_ar">Switch to abstract reasoning.</string>
    <string name="switch_sv">Switch to spatial visualization.</string>
    <string name="sp_section_title">Spatial Visualization</string>
    <!--Context switch -->
</resources>
